Rajkumar Selvakumar

Front-end Developer

+917708461341

raj1711dell@gmail.com

Portfolio



PROFILE

Having 2 years of experience as a React JS developer with diversified exposure in design development and implementation of web based application. Good experience in JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, BootStrap, ReactStrap, Redux typescript, and web3 integration.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- React JS
- JavaScript
- CSS3
- HTML5
- BootStrap
- ReactStrap
- TypeScript
- PWA
- GIT, filezilla
- Web development
- React Native
- Web3 Integration
- Next JS

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH

TAMIL

EXPERIENCES

Ecrubit Software Services Pvt Ltd | June 2022- July 2023 Software Engineer

- Make good technical decisions that provide solutions to business challenges and Resolve complex technical design and issues. Possess up-to-date knowledge of technological developments in the industry.
- Writing reliable, reusable, and practical code for the high availability Worked with partners and clients to figure out the best protocols and designs to solve business Problems.
- Identify ideas to improve system performance and impact availability. Designing responsive Web pages.

Seminal | July 2023- Present

Front-End Engineer

 Contributed to the development and enhancement of innovative products as a dedicated Front-end Developer at an Australian industry ensuring seamless user experiences and incorporating cutting-edge technologies to drive the company's success in the competitive market.

EDUCATION

Electrical Electronics Engineering | 2017 - 2021 Vel Tech Multi Tech Dr Rangarajan Dr.Sagunthala Engineering College

CGPA: 7.57

HSC(Maths/Biology) | 2016 - 2017 Devi Matric Higher Secondary School

Percentage: 85%

SSLC | 2014 - 2015

Devi Matric Higher Secondary School

Percentage: 96%

PROJECT WORKS

Project 1: Store My Goods (Front-end React Developer)

Duration: 6 months

Team Size: 1

Technologies Used: React JS

- Store My Goods is an Platform offering warehouse facilities to store your household things, car, bike etc.
- There are three panels OrderIntake, Customer, and Admin Panel.
- User can give order through orderIntake and Customer panel by providing details of storing items, pickup Address, Drop Address and documents.
- Client can manage all the frontend data using Admin Panel

Project 2: Causevest (Front-end React Developer)

Duration: Long term

Team Size: 1

Technologies Used: React JS

- Causevest is a digital giving platform used to raise funds for people who need money for their Education, Health, Invention etc..
- My Role: Fixing Bugs in the production

Project 3: Ticketshala (Front-end React Developer)

Duration: Long term

Team Size: 1

Technologies Used: React Js, TypeScript, Laravel for Backend

- Ticketshala is a online flight Ticket booking platform
- My Role: Fixing Bug on production and creating some responsive reusable UI components using Typescript

Project 4: MoonClub

Project 5: Super Psyched Collective

Project 6: Last Soul Island

Project 7: Exceed

- All these NFT projects are based on Minting the unique NFT Using Ethereum Cryptocurrency
- My Role: Creating responsive UI using bootstrap and Creating & integrating Web3 functionality, Wallet Connect with MetaMask and Use-Winter Credit Card Using Solidity ABI file.